Register of the Freda Utley Papers, 1886-1978
Hoover Institution Archives
Freda Utley Papers,
1886-1978
78056
Utley, Freda, 1898-1978
87 manuscript boxes, 11 envelopes (37.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, relating to social and political conditions in Russia, Japan, and China in the interwar period; the Sino-Japanese conflict; World War II; American relations with China; Germany in the post-World War II reconstruction period; social and political developments in the Middle East; and anti-communism in the United States.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1978.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Anti-communist movements--United States.; Communism.; Nuremberg Trial of Major German War Criminals, 1945-1946.; Reconstruction (1939-1951)--Germany.; Sino-Japanese Conflict, 1937-1945.; World War, 1939-1945.; China.; China--Foreign relations--United States.; China--Politics and government.; Germany.; Germany--History--1945-1955.; Japan.; Japan--Politics and government--1912-1945.; Middle East.; Middle East--Politics and government.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--Politics and government--1917-1936.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Foreign relations--China.
Biographical Note
1898, Jan. 23 Born, London, England
1923 B.A., London University
1925 M.A., London University
1926-1928 Research fellow, London School of Economics
1928 Joined British Communist Party. Marriage to Arcadi Berdichevsky
1930 Took up residence in Soviet Union
1931 Author, Lancashire and the Far East. Membership in British Communist Party lapsed
1932-1936 Senior scientific worker, Institute of World Economy and Politics, Academy of Sciences, Moscow
1936 Arrest and disappearance of husband. Return to England. Author, Japan's Feet of Clay
1938 War correspondent in China. Author, Japan's Gamble in China
1939 Author, China at War. Took up residence in United States
1940 Author, The Dream We Lost
1941-1945 Economic consultant, Starr, Park and Freeman Company, New York
1945-1946 War correspondent in China
1947 Author, Last Chance in China
1948 Author, Lost Illusion (revised version of The Dream We Lost)
1949 Author, The High Cost of Vengeance
1950 Naturalized as citizen of United States
1950-1954 Anti-communist witness, various Congressional hearings. Testified against Owen Lattimore
1951 Author, The China Story
1957 Author, Will the Middle East Go West?
1970 Author, Odyssey of a Liberal
1978, Jan. 21 Died, Washington, D.C.
Series Description
- Biographical File, 1937-1978. (Boxes 1-2.)
  Biographical sketches, clippings, interviews, lecture notices, and miscellany, relating to the life of Freda Utley, arranged alphabetically by form
- Correspondence, Alphabetical, 1886-1977. (Boxes 2-13.)
  Significant correspondence of Freda Utley, arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Includes a few letters neither from nor to Freda Utley, arranged alphabetically by author
- Correspondence, Chronological, 1919-1976. (Boxes 14-18.)
  Less significant correspondence of Freda Utley, arranged chronologically. Includes a few letters neither from nor to Freda Utley
- Speeches And Writings, Dated, 1930-1974. (Boxes 18-29.)
  Drafts and/or printed copies of speeches and writings by Freda Utley, arranged chronologically. Includes reviews of her books and some related promotional material
- Speeches And Writings, Undated. (Boxes 29-32.)
  Drafts of undated, and mainly unpublished, speeches and writings by Freda Utley, arranged alphabetically by title. In a few cases includes printed copies of articles whose publication dates could not be ascertained
- Speeches And Writings, Fragments Of, n.d. (Boxes 32-36.)
  Fragments of drafts for unidentifiable speeches and writings by Freda Utley, unarranged
- Notebooks, n.d. (Boxes 37-41.)
  Notes assembled by Freda Utley for use in her speeches and writings, not readily divisible by subject, unarranged
- Subject File, 1936-1976. (Boxes 42-84.)
  Clippings, serial issues, pamphlets, reprints, leaflets, bulletins, newsletters, other printed matter, typed copies and translations of printed matter, press summaries, press releases, news dispatches, speech transcripts, memoranda, lists, notes, and miscellany, relating broadly to contemporaneous political, social and economic conditions in most parts of the world, arranged alphabetically by subject. In most cases subjects are names of countries or other geographical areas
- Audio-Visual File.
  See Photo Card Catalog
Container List
- Biographical File, 1937-1978
  - Biographical sketches (Box 1., Folder 1)
  - Clippings (Folder 2-4)
  - Immigration materials (affidavits, applications, memoranda, and bills, relating to the admission of Freda Utley to the United States) (Folder 5)
  - Interviews (summaries and notes of interviews of Freda Utley by others) (Folder 6)
  - Lecture notices (Box 2., Folder l)
  - Miscellany (includes certificates, and memorial service program) (Folder 2)
  - Publicity materials (press releases, and brochures) (Folder 3)
- Correspondence, Alphabetical, 1886-1977
  - Achenbach, Ernst, 1952-1954 (Box 2., Folder 4)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on the Middle East, 1968 (Folder 5)
  - Ahrens, Hanns Dietrich, 1953-1970 (Folder 6)
  - Alsop, Joseph, 1952 (Folder 7)
  - American China Policy Association, 1944-1949 (Folder 8)
  - American China Policy Association, 1950-1959 (Box 3., Folder 1-2)
  - American Committee for Christian Refugees, 1940 (Folder 3)
  - American Committee for Non-Participation in Japanese Aggression, 1938 (Folder 4)
  - American Council for Judaism, 1956-1959 (Folder 5)
  - American Friends of the Middle East, 1957-1958 (Folder 6)
  - American Friends' Service Committee, 1941-1958 (Folder 7)
  - American Legion, 1953-1955 (Folder 8)
  - American Legion Magazine, 1950-1953 (Folder 9)
  - American Mercury, 1942-1956 (Folder 10)
  - American Middle East Rehabilitation, 1964-1968 (Folder 11)
  - Amini, Ali, 1957-1958 (Folder 12)
  - App, Austin J., 1950-1974 (Folder 13)
  - Arabian American Oil Company, 1957 (Folder 14)
  - Asha, Rafik, 1957 (Folder 15)
  - Asian Peoples' Anti-Communist League, 1956-1968 (Folder 16)
  - Atequi, Abdul Rahman, 1971-1973 (Folder 17)
  - Atlantic Monthly, 1941-1968 (Folder 18)
  - Baird, Alexander, 1944-1955 (Box 4., Folder 1)
  - Balabanoff, Angelica, 1944-1945 (Folder 2)
  - Baldwin, Roger N., 1942 (Folder 3)
  - Barnes, Harry Elmer, 1951-1957 (Folder 4)
  - Barten, Ernst H., 1949-1971 (Folder 5)
  - Battle, Lucius D., 1965-1971 (Folder 6)
  - Bauer, Maximilian B., 1960 (Folder 7)
  - Bell Syndicate, 1948 (Folder 8)
  - Bertrand Russell Archives, 1969-1970 (Folder 9)
  - Besant, Annie, 1886 (Folder 10)
  - Biddle, Francis, 1942 (Folder 11)
  - Bingham, Alfred M. see Common Sense
  - Bishara, Abdulla Yaccoub, 1973 (Folder 12)
  - Blake, Peter, 1951-1961 (Folder 13)
  - Blomberg, Frary von, Baron, 1951-1971 (Folder 14)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1947-1950 (Folder 15)
  - Boeker, Alexander, 1948 (Folder 16)
  - Boettiger, Anna Roosevelt, 1942 (Folder 17)
  - Bourguiba, Habib, Jr., 1962 (Folder 18)
  - Bowles, Chester, 1941-1944 (Folder 19)
  - Boxer, Charles, 1939 (Folder 20)
  - Brailsford, H. N., 1954 (Folder 21)
  - Brandt, Karl, 1949 (Folder 22)
  - Braun, Freiherr von, 1951-1958 (Folder 23)
  - Brewster, Owen, 1950 (Folder 24)
  - Bridges, Styles, 1953-1958 (Folder 25)
  - Bucerius, Gerd, 1950-1951 (Folder 26)
  - Buchanan, Rab, 1928-1959 (Folder 27)
  - Buck, Pearl S., 1940-1945 (Folder 28)
  - Buckley, James L., 1971 (Folder 29)
  - Buckley, William F., Jr. see National Review
  - Buffett, Howard, 1952 (Folder 30)
  - Burton, Dora, 1946-1950 (Folder 31)
  - Burton, Wilbur, 1948-1954 (Folder 32)
  - Cain, Harry P., 1954 (Folder 33)
  - Calverton, V. F., n.d. (Folder 34)
  - Campaign for the 48 States, 1955 (Folder 35)
  - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, 1958 (Folder 36)
  - Capper, Arthur, 1943 (Folder 37)
  - Carlson, Evans, 1939-1946 (Folder 38)
  - Carr, E. H., 1936 (Folder 39)
  - Chamberlin, William Henry, 1952-1955 (Folder 40)
  - Chambrun, Jacques, 1947-1954 (Folder 41)
  - Chanderli, Abdul Kader, 1957 (Folder 42)
  - Chang, Hajji Yusuf, 1956-1960 (Folder 43)
  - Chang, Kuo-sin, 1948 (Folder 44)
  - Chavez, Dennis, 1950 (Folder 45)
  - Chen, Chih-mai, 1945-1972 (Folder 46)
  - Chen, Chih-ping, 1957 (Box 5., Folder 1)
  - Chiang, Kai-shek, 1956-1957 (Folder 2)
  - China Weekly Review, 1938-1948 (Folder 3)
  - Christian Anti-Communist Crusade, 1974 (Folder 4)
  - Cincinnati Enquirer, 1954-1957 (Folder 5)
  - Clay, Lucius D., 1948 (Folder 6)
  - Cohn, Roy, 1954 (Folder 7)
  - Columbia Lecture Bureau, 1940-1950 (Folder 8)
  - Common Sense, 1940-1944 (Folder 9)
  - Commonweal, 1952 (Folder 10)
  - Congress for Cultural Freedom, 1950-1954 (Folder 11)
  - Congress of Freedom, 1955-1956 (Folder 12)
  - Cooke, Charles M., 1955-1963 (Folder 13)
  - Crane, John B., 1949-1955 (Folder 14)
  - Dallas, George, 1954-1955 (Folder 15)
  - Degras, Jane, 1941-1970 (Folder 16)
  - Dennis, Lawrence, 1955. see also SUBJECT FILE (Folder 17)
  - Dessouki, Salah, 1961-1964 (Folder 18)
  - Devin-Adair Company, 1958-1973 (Folder 19)
  - Dewar, Rita, 1941-1972 (Folder 20)
  - Dirksen, Everett McKinley, 1964 (Folder 21)
  - Dodd, Thomas J., 1962-1965 (Folder 22)
  - Dodd, Mead and Company, 1970-1972 (Folder 23)
  - Donovan, William J., 1948 (Folder 24)
  - Dooley, Thomas A., 1957-1958 (Folder 25)
  - Dooman, Eugene H., 1952 (Folder 26)
  - Douglas, Paul H., 1955-1958 (Folder 27)
  - Duehring, Walter, 1960-1968 (Folder 28)
  - Duff, J. Arthur, 1956 (Folder 29)
  - Durdin, Tillman, 1962 (Folder 30)
  - Eastland, James O., 1955 (Folder 31)
  - Eastman, Max, 1940-1966. see also SUBJECT FILE (Folder 32)
  - Eaton, Charles A., n.d. (Folder 33)
  - Elliott, William Yandell, 1950 (Folder 34)
  - Emmet, Christopher, 1947 (Folder 35)
  - Epstein, Julius, 1951-1953 (Folder 36)
  - Ernst August, Prince, 1952-1953 (Folder 37)
  - Evans, M. Stanton, 1955-1970 (Folder 38)
  - Evans, Medford. see Facts Forum
  - Evans, Rowland, Jr., 1971 (Folder 39)
  - Everett, Willis M., Jr., 1954 (Folder 40)
  - Faber and Faber Company, 1939-1974 (Folder 41)
  - Facts Forum, 1954-1955 (Folder 42)
  - Ferguson, Homer, 1944-1952 (Folder 43)
  - Ferlisi, Alfredo, 1960-1971 (Folder 44)
  - Fischer, Hanns, 1958-1970 (Box 6., Folder 1)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1940 (Folder 2)
  - Flanders, Ralph E., 1957-1958 (Folder 3)
  - Flynn, John T., 1944-1949 (Folder 4)
  - Foreign Affairs, 1940 (Folder 5)
  - Forster, Clifford, 1953-1954 (Folder 6)
  - Fortune, 1942-1949 (Folder 7)
  - Foundation for Foreign Affairs, 1950-1958 (Folder 8)
  - Fraser, A. G., 1939 (Folder 9)
  - Freeman, 1950-1955 (Folder 10)
  - Frei, Erich, 1953-1970 (Folder 11)
  - Friends of Democracy, 1951 (Folder 12)
  - Fulbright, J. William, 1971-1972 (Folder 13)
  - George Allen and Unwin Company, 1949-1955 (Folder 14)
  - Goldsmith, Sybil, 1949-1968 (Folder 15)
  - Gould, Randall, 1939-1940. see also Starr, Park and Freeman Company (Folder 16)
  - Graves, Sidney, 1944-1961 (Folder 17)
  - Green, Theodore Francis, 1958 (Folder 18)
  - Grenfell, Russell, 1953 (Folder 19)
  - Grundner, Gerhard, 1952-1953 (Folder 20)
  - Haikal, Y., 1958 (Folder 21)
  - Hamilton, Edith, 1945-1949 (Folder 22)
  - Hanighen, Frank C. see Human Events
  - Hankinson, Norman, 1953-1954 (Folder 23)
  - Hart, Merwin K. see National Economic Council
  - Harten, K. P., 1952-1953 (Folder 24)
  - Hatem, Abdul Kader, 1963 (Folder 25)
  - Hatfield, Mark O., 1971 (Folder 26)
  - Hebert, Edward, 1971 (Folder 27)
  - Heffron, Edward J., 1952-1953 (Folder 28)
  - Heimlich, William F., 1955 (Folder 29)
  - Henderson, Loy W., 1940-1969 (Folder 30)
  - Henry Holt and Company, 1958 (Folder 31)
  - Henry Regnery Company, 1948-1959 (Folder 32)
  - Henry Regnery Company, 1961-1977 (Box 7., Folder 1)
  - Herron, George B., 1958 (Folder 2)
  - Heymann, Egon, 1950-1958 (Folder 3)
  - Hickenlooper, Bourke B., 1958-1966 (Folder 4)
  - Hill and Knowlton Company, 1952-1970 (Folder 5)
  - Ho, Shai Lai, 1955-1972 (Folder 6)
  - Hocking, William Ernest, 1963-1964 (Folder 7)
  - Hogan, John F., Jr., 1967-1972 (Folder 8)
  - Holman, Rufus C., 1944 (Folder 9)
  - Holmes, John Haynes, 1942 (Folder 10)
  - Holt, L. Emmett, Jr. see American Middle East Rehabilitation
  - Holt, Olivia, 1964 (Folder 11)
  - Hook, Sidney, 1941-1970 (Folder 12)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1949-1955 (Folder 13)
  - Hu, Chiu-yuan, 1956-1958 (Folder 14)
  - Hu, Shih, 1942-1944 (Folder 15)
  - Hudson, Geoffrey, 1938-1970 (Folder 16)
  - Human Events, 1944-1956 (Folder 17)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1957-1964 (Folder 18)
  - Hunt, H. L., 1956 (Folder 19)
  - Hussein, Ahmed, 1957 (Folder 20)
  - Independent Labour Party, 1939-1949 (Folder 21)
  - Jackson, Henry M., 1971 (Folder 22)
  - Jamali, Mohammad Fadhel, 1957 (Folder 23)
  - Javits, Jacob K., 1969 (Folder 24)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1942-1943 (Folder 25)
  - John Day Company, 1940-1946 (Folder 26)
  - Johnson, Philip, 1963-1965 (Folder 27)
  - Judd, Walter H., 1944-1961 (Folder 28)
  - Jung, Ernst, 1955 (Folder 29)
  - Kalckreuth, Gerty, Graefin, 1958-1963 (Folder 30)
  - Kalckreuth, Joachim, Graf, 1952-1965 (Folder 31)
  - Kamel, Mostafa, 1958 (Box 8., Folder 1)
  - Kampelman, Max M., 1968-1970 (Folder 2)
  - Kao, Tsung-wu, 1943-1944 (Folder 3)
  - Keedick, Lee, 1947-1953 (Folder 4)
  - Kem, James P., 1951 (Folder 5)
  - Kennedy, John F., 1957 (Folder 6)
  - Kerensky, Alexander, 1940 (Folder 7)
  - Kesselring, Albert, 1953-1958 (Folder 8)
  - Kfoury, Robert, 1957-1959 (Folder 9)
  - Kilpatrick, James J., 1957 (Folder 10)
  - Klein, Herbert G., 1971 (Folder 11)
  - Klingelhofer, Albert, 1952-1961 (Folder 12)
  - Knowland, William F., 1954-1958 (Folder 13)
  - Kohlberg, Alfred. see American China Policy Association
  - Kranzbuehler, Otto, 1953-1962 (Folder 14)
  - Kuebler, Paul C., 1948-1952 (Folder 15)
  - Kuhn, Irene Corbally, 1947-1977 (Folder 16)
  - Laird, Melvin R., 1971-1974 (Folder 17)
  - Langer, William, 1949-1954 (Folder 18)
  - Laski, Harold J., 1937 (Folder 19)
  - Lattimore, Owen, 1952. see also Schmidt, Egan and Murray; BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, under Clippings; and SUBJECT FILE (Folder 20)
  - Leinfelder, Georg, 1953 (Folder 21)
  - Levine, Isaac Don, 1946-1963 (Folder 22)
  - Lewis, Fulton, Jr., 1951 (Folder 23)
  - Life, 1945-1954 (Folder 24)
  - Lilienthal, Alfred, 1971 (Folder 25)
  - Lindbergh, Anne Morrow, 1944 (Folder 26)
  - Lindbergh, Charles A., 1970 (Folder 27)
  - Loeb, William, 1952-1973 (Folder 28)
  - Loewenstein, Hubertus zu, Prince, 1953-1955 (Folder 29)
  - Longworth, Alice Roosevelt, 1944 (Folder 30)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1956 (Folder 31)
  - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1944-1947 (Folder 32)
  - Luce, Henry R. see Life. and Time
  - Lyons, Eugene. see American Mercury. and Reader's Digest
  - MacArthur, Douglas, 1954 (Folder 33)
  - McCarran, Pat, 1951-1952 (Folder 34)
  - McCarthy, Joseph R., 1950-1954. see also SUBJECT FILE (Folder 35)
  - Macdonald, Dwight, 1962-1967 (Folder 36)
  - McKneally, Martin B., 1951-1953 (Folder 37)
  - McNamara, Robert, 1972 (Folder 38)
  - Maloney, Francis, 1943-1944 (Folder 39)
  - Mandel, Benjamin, 1950-1956 (Folder 40)
  - Manes, Alfred, 1942-1943 (Folder 41)
  - Mannin, Ethel, 1964 (Folder 42)
  - Marquand, John P., 1944-1948 (Folder 43)
  - Mason, Frank E., 1947-1962 (Folder 44)
  - Matthews, J. B., 1942 (Folder 45)
  - Maurer, Herrymon, 1948 (Folder 46)
  - Menjou, Adolphe, 1954-1955 (Box 9., Folder 1)
  - Miles, Milton E., n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Mohr, Gretel, 1952-1963 (Folder 3)
  - Morley, Felix. see Human Events
  - Muggeridge, Malcolm, 1948-1971 (Folder 4)
  - Mundt, Karl E., 1946-1964 (Folder 5)
  - Nasser, Gamal Abdel, 1959-1965. see also SUBJECT FILE, under Egypt (Folder 6)
  - National Economic Council, 1952-1972 (Folder 7)
  - National Press, 1967-1970 (Folder 8)
  - National Review, 1952-1971 (Folder 9)
  - Nedelmann, Heinz, 1949-1976 (Folder 10)
  - Nelson, Frederic. see Saturday Evening Post
  - Nelson, Sylvia, 1942-1945 (Folder 11)
  - New Statesman and Nation, 1939 (Folder 12)
  - New York Times, 1947-1968 (Folder 13)
  - News Chronicle (London), 1938 (Folder 14)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1955-1971 (Folder 15)
  - Noelke (H. H.) Verlag, 1951-1957 (Folder 16)
  - North, Robert C., n.d. (Folder 17)
  - Norton, Florence, 1951-1966. see also Freeman (Folder 18)
  - Nye, Gerald P., 1943-1944 (Folder 19)
  - O'Conor, Herbert, 1952 (Folder 20)
  - Odlum, Victor W., 1948-1949 (Folder 21)
  - Oeftering, H. M., 1953 (Folder 22)
  - Ogren, Pat, 1958-1959 (Folder 23)
  - O'Hara, Joseph P., 1941-1944 (Folder 24)
  - Palestine Arab Refugee Office, 1956-1957 (Folder 25)
  - Papen, Franz von, 1948-1954 (Folder 26)
  - Papen, Franz von, Jr., 1958-1959 (Folder 27)
  - Pathfinder, 1952-1953 (Folder 28)
  - Pearson, Drew, 1954 (Folder 29)
  - Pegler, Westbrook, n.d. (Folder 30)
  - Phillips, Emily, 1933-1963 (Folder 31)
  - Plesse Verlag, 1958-1963 (Folder 32)
  - Ponce de Leon, Guy, 1965 (Folder 33)
  - Powell, J. B. see China Weekly Review. and SUBJECT FILE, under Eastman, Max
  - Princeton University, 1941-1944 (Folder 34)
  - Progressive, 1944 (Folder 35)
  - Rahim, Kamil A., 1957-1960 (Folder 36)
  - Ram Goel, Sita, 1953-1958 (Folder 37)
  - Ram Swarup, 1955-1974 (Folder 38)
  - al-Rashid, Rashid, 1973 (Box 10., Folder 1)
  - Reader's Digest, 1942-1974 (Folder 2-3)
  - Redpath Bureau, 1951-1970 (Folder 4)
  - Regnery, Henry. see Henry Regnery Company
  - Regnery, William H. see Foundation for Foreign Affairs
  - Reimann, Guenter, 1937-1974 (Folder 5)
  - Religion and Society, 1970-1971 (Folder 6)
  - Reporter, 1952-1957 (Folder 7)
  - Rheinlaender, Paul, 1952-1965 (Folder 8)
  - Ribbentrop, Annelies von, 1958 (Folder 9)
  - Richardson Foundation, 1956 (Folder 10)
  - Rifa'i, Abdul Monem, n.d. (Folder 11)
  - Robertson, Walter S., 1954-1957 (Folder 12)
  - Roechling, Ernst, 1955 (Folder 13)
  - Rohland, Walter, 1952-1966 (Folder 14)
  - Rolland, Romain, 1937 (Folder 15)
  - Rountree, William M., 1957-1958 (Folder 16)
  - Russell, Bertrand, 1930-1968. see also Bertrand Russell Archives; and SUBJECT FILE (Folder 17)
  - Russell, Patricia, 1937-1961 (Folder 18)
  - Russell, Richard B., 1944 (Folder 19)
  - Ryskind, Morrie, 1955 (Folder 20)
  - St. George, Katherine, 1950-1964 (Folder 21)
  - Sansom, Sir George, 1940-1944 (Folder 22)
  - Sansom, Lady Katherine, 1939-1954 (Folder 23)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1942-1974 (Folder 24)
  - Saturday Review of Literature, 1951-1961 (Folder 25)
  - Sayegh, Fayez A., 1957 (Folder 26)
  - Schacht, Hjalmar, 1953-1954 (Folder 27)
  - Schelfhout, Paul, 1960 (Folder 28)
  - Schlafly, Phyllis, 1969-1970 (Folder 29)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr., 1961-1970 (Folder 30)
  - Schmid, Karlo, 1950 (Folder 31)
  - Schmidt, Egan and Murray (law firm), 1952 (Folder 32)
  - Schoknecht, Werner, 1953-1954 (Box 11., Folder 1)
  - Schumacher-Nelles, Johann, 1949-1950 (Folder 2)
  - Scott, Charles Ernest, 1949-1956 (Folder 3)
  - Scott, H. Vernon, 1970 (Folder 4)
  - Selvage, Lee and Chase Company, 1953-1955 (Folder 5)
  - Shah, Konsin C., 1957-1971 (Folder 6)
  - Shakespeare, Frank, 1969-1970 (Folder 7)
  - Sharaf, Abdul Hamid, 1971-1972 (Folder 8)
  - Shaw, George Bernard, 1937 (Folder 9)
  - Shehab, Fakri, 1963-1964 (Folder 10)
  - Sign, 1947 (Folder 11)
  - Skoniecki, A. A., 1945 (Folder 12)
  - Skorzeny, Ilse, 1954-1958 (Folder 13)
  - Skorzeny, Otto, 1954-1959 (Folder 14)
  - Smal-Stocki, Roman, 1953 (Folder 15)
  - Smedley, Agnes, 1944 (Folder 16)
  - Smith, Margaret Chase, 1951 (Folder 17)
  - Smith, Truman, 1944-1953 (Folder 18)
  - Sohl, Hans-Guenther, 1963 (Folder 19)
  - Sokolsky, George E., 1950-1954 (Folder 20)
  - Sourwine, J. G., 1972 (Folder 21)
  - Souvarine, Boris, n.d. (Folder 22)
  - Speidel, Hans, 1949-1954 (Folder 23)
  - Spiegel, 1952 (Folder 24)
  - Staar, Richard F., 1956 (Folder 25)
  - Starr, Park and Freeman Company, 1941-1971. see also Subject File (Folder 26)
  - Stennes, Walther, 1952-1972 (Folder 27)
  - Stimson, Henry L., 1939 (Folder 28)
  - Stinnes, Otto, 1953-1955 (Folder 29)
  - Stratemeyer, George E., 1955 (Folder 30)
  - Strausz-Hupe, Robert, 1951-1956 (Folder 31)
  - Taft, Robert A., 1944-1953 (Folder 32)
  - Tariki, Abdullah H., 1960-1961 (Folder 33)
  - Taylor, Telford, 1948 (Folder 34)
  - Thomas, Norman, 1944-1964 (Box 12., Folder 1)
  - Thompson, Dorothy, 1955-1958 (Folder 2)
  - Thompson, H. Keith, 1954 (Folder 3)
  - Thompson, Llewellyn E., 1962 (Folder 4)
  - Time, 1940-1970 (Folder 5)
  - Toynbee, Arnold, 1961 (Folder 6)
  - Triumph, 1967 (Folder 7)
  - Tyson, Francis D., 1943-1944 (Folder 8)
  - U.S. Central Intelligence Agency, 1947-1958 (Folder 9)
  - U.S. Consulate General, Montreal, Canada, 1940-1944 (Folder 10)
  - U.S. Immigration and Naturalization Service, 1940-1945 (Folder 11)
  - Utley, Emily, 1926-1945 (Folder 12-13)
  - Utley, Emsie, 1933-1961 (Folder 14)
  - Utley, Jon, 1941-1973 (Folder 15)
  - Utley, Temple, 1913-1935 (Folder 16)
  - Utley, William, 1911-1917 (Folder 17)
  - Valdeiglesias, Jose Ignacio, Marques, 1954-1958 (Folder 18)
  - Veale, F. J. P., 1953-1961 (Folder 19)
  - Verlag Fritz Schlichtenmayer, 1961-1963 (Folder 20)
  - Verlag Karl Heinz Priester, 1960-1961 (Folder 21)
  - Villard, Oswald Garrison, 1944-1945 (Box 13., Folder l)
  - Voorhis, Jerry, 1942-1944 (Folder 2)
  - Wagner, Hans, 1950 (Folder 3)
  - Wahba, Moustapha, 1960 (Folder 4)
  - Waldman, Louis, 1970 (Folder 5)
  - Walsh, Richard J. see John Day Company
  - Walter, Heinrich, 1949 (Folder 6)
  - Washington Post, 1952-1970 (Folder 7)
  - Webb, Sidney, 1936 (Folder 8)
  - Weber, Erhart, 1948-1969 (Folder 9)
  - Weber, Wilhelm, 1952 (Folder 10)
  - Wedemeyer, Albert C., 1946-1961. see also SUBJECT FILE (Folder 11)
  - Wehner, Herbert, 1952 (Folder 12)
  - Wei, James, 1972 (Folder 13)
  - Werner, Franz, 1949-1953 (Folder 14)
  - Wheeler, Burton K., 1944 (Folder 15)
  - White, Harry Dexter, 1945 (Folder 16)
  - White, William L., 1948-1955 (Folder 17)
  - William, Maurice, 1944 (Folder 18)
  - William Collins Sons and Company, 1970-1971 (Folder 19)
  - William Volker Fund, 1953-1954 (Folder 20)
  - Williams, C. Dickerman, 1943-1961 (Folder 21)
  - Wilms, Ernst, 1948-1955 (Folder 22)
  - Wittfogel, Karl A., 1951. see also SUBJECT FILE (Folder 23)
  - Wolfe, Bertram D., 1946 (Folder 24)
  - Wolfe, Ella, 1945 (Folder 25)
  - Women for Nixon-Agnew, 1968 (Folder 26)
  - Wood, Robert E., 1942-1958 (Folder 27)
  - Yeh, George, 1954-1968 (Folder 28)
  - Young, A. Morgan, 1939-1941 (Folder 29)
  - Zapp, Manfred, 1950-1958 (Folder 30)
  - Zeit, 1953-1955 (Folder 31)
  - Zeitschrift fuer Geopolitik, 1952-1954 (Folder 32)
  - Zezulak, Hans H., 1949-1952 (Folder 33)
- Correspondence, Chronological, 1919-1976
  - 1919 (Box 14., Folder 1)
  - 1923 (Folder 2)
  - 1930 (Folder 3)
  - 1931 (Folder 4)
  - 1933 (Folder 5)
  - 1935 (Folder 6)
  - 1936 (Folder 7)
  - 1937 (Folder 8)
  - 1938 (Folder 9)
  - 1939 (Folder 10)
  - 1940 (Folder 11)
  - 1941 (Folder 12)
  - 1942 (Folder 13)